Maximilian Hvesser-Lewis

Senior Software Engineer

Experienced developer with a focus on crafting intuitive and functional user experiences, combining cutting-edge technology skills with strong communication, helping to bridge product and technology, where I can realise the precise needs of the project at hand.

1255 Seymour St, Vancouver

maxhvesser@gmail.com

778 266 1845

hvesserlewis.com

Skills

Kotlin Java Kotlin multiplatform Android SDK Dependency Injection (Hilt/Koin) Persistence (Room/SQL/Proto) Jetpack

Networking (Retrofit/Ktor) Kotlin Coroutines/Flows ReactJS Typescript NextJS Git

Work experience

Senior Software Engineer

Vipps MobilePay

2021 - Present

Oslo, Norway • Vancouver, Canada

- Lead the development of an entirely new credit financial product for Android users, leading to increased company revenue.
- Transitioned the core payment flow UI from XML to Jetpack Compose. This directly decreased the user drop-off rate when paying, and increased
 user engagement.
- Abstracted and streamlined core payment services into standardized modules, leading to increased efficiency across multiple domain teams, allowing for quick integration with the payment flow.

Senior Android Engineer

FINN.no

2019 - 2021 Oslo, Norway

- Developed an open-source image gallery that increased the companies' developer presence in the community as well providing users with a new immersive image-experience.
- Lead the development of a notification system for Android users. The new outreach system drastically improved user enganement and directly
 increased the communication power with customers.

Lead Android Engineer

DTT

2017 - 2019 Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Managed the development of high-quality and cost-effective native Android applications, successfully converting prospective customers into sales.
- Mentored a team of developers, driving collaboration, where I significantly increased productivity.
- Carried out high-level processes, such as, app releasing, dependency management and code optimization, leading to inceased scalability and maintainability of projects.

Software Engineer

DTT

2016 - 2017 Amsterdam, The Netherlands

- Provided a full range of consultant services, including; the development of new native mobile applications, adding features to existing codebases and in-depth code analysis.
- Notably increased client satisfaction by routinely meeting deadlines and diligently taking a detailed approach to the tasks I undertook.

Junior Software Engineer

Bandvulc

2013 - 2016 Plymouth, United Kingdom

• Created an always-on service that allowed the app to track the whereabouts of drivers when on the road. This functionality greatly increased the logistical overview of the entire fleet, making it easier to understand the status of each driver, in real-time.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science

University of Plymouth 2014 - 2017

Bachelor of Psychology

Staffordshire University 2011 - 2014